ANUSHA NAIR

Dombivli, Thane - 421201 · Mobile: 9619495435

Email: anunair.127@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile · https://www.linkedin.com/in/anusha-nair-b2b52b50

IT specialist with a Bachelor Degree in Information Technology. I have more than 9+ years' experience in the industry and I am proficient with a wide variety of security, engineering, networking and managing operating system software. My objective is to share my experience and knowledge to enhance, fortify and introduce systems being a part of your organization.

STRENGTHS

- Bachelor degree in Information Technology
- 9+ years' experience in IT industry
- Strong technical and interpersonal communication
- Team Oriented
- Self-Starter with an accurate and detail-oriented work ethic
- Strong sense of responsibility

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2018-PRESENT

IT MANAGER, SOFTWARE; EUROKIDS GROUP

- Plans, designs and develops programs; tests, maintains and documents cloud-hosted, web-based systems management facilities.
- Overall management of the Knowledge Management process which includes content research, assets management, planning and evaluation; and creation of project proposals.
- Performs development activities for customized software applications that have been designed to support the objectives of the organization.
- Manages all software development applications; handles bug/ fixes, modernization programs and schedules enhancement activities.
- Serves as the Project Manager for all software development related projects; prepares and establishes budgets, priority list, risk management parameters and ensures that all deadlines and timetables are consistently met.
- LMS, HRMS, website content management and reporting modules are the major project areas.
- Experience using Zoho One, Google Apps for Business, Microsoft 365 tools, Articulate 360

MAY 2014 - MAY 2018

IT FACILITATOR; DON BOSCO INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

- Maintenance of the LMS, mobile app, HRMS and reporting modules.
- Managing the website content hosted on WordPress platform and all social media platforms (Facebook, LinkedIn etc.).
- Preparing all kinds of presentation material required for management as well as organizational events which includes release of newsletters and annual reports.
- Preparing vendor quotations as per yearly IT budget.
- Facilitate monthly meetings with clients to document requirements and explore potential solutions.

JANUARY 2014-APRIL 2014

WEB ANALYST; ACCENTURE

- Assist in developing the strategies and execute key initiatives for B2B web site conversion improvements.
- Provides regular reports enterprise wide on website performance.
- Create digital dashboards and performance summary reports for various business units and management.
- Participate in online product and program development to ensure tracking and measurement of new products and establish baseline performance expectations.
- Work with advertising agency and members of the marketing team to identify opportunities to improve ad performance, promotions and web sales.
- Improve conversion rate on underperforming products against offline performance.
- Make recommendations to senior management on ways to improve the website.

NOVEMBER 2010-DECEMBER 2013

CONTENT MANAGER; TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

- Drive site improvements to completion by coordinating with project managers, web developers, product managers, designers, vendors, and other merchandisers.
- Assist in the development of metrics for measuring efficiency of new workflows and develop shortand long-term plans for driving efficiency.
- Work with the Marketing Manager to develop timely and relevant communications for various trigger points in the customer lifecycle.
- Develop targeting strategies that will improve marketing and merchandising performance.
- Manage / Create / Edit web content and provide relevant support.
- Work closely with assistant editors and other content managers to foster the creation of timely, accurate, informative and thought-provoking stories.

EDUCATION

APRIL 2019

PGDM – IT PROJECT MANAGEMENT, WELINGKAR INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT DEVELOPMENT & RESEARCH

APRIL 2010

BSC-INFORMATION TECHINOLOGY, MODEL COLLEGE OF SCIENCE AND ARTS

APRIL 2007

HSC-SCIENCE, V.K.K.MENON COLLEGE OF SCIENCE AND COMMERCE

SKILLS

- IT Administration
- Database Management
- Content management
- Team Management

- Presentation skills
- Time Management
- Problem solving
- Knowledge Management

WORKSHOPS/TRAININGS ATTENDED

- Google Apps for Business
- CAT 1 Category PYP Certification Role of IT in education
- Microsoft 365 tools
- Implementation of Microsoft Bots
- Implementation Guidance for ISO 9001:2015